<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Packrat on experiments with R</title>
    <link>https://czeildi.github.io/tags/packrat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Packrat on experiments with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://czeildi.github.io/tags/packrat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R package check with Docker on Codeship</title>
      <link>https://czeildi.github.io/2017/09/17/r-pkg-check-with-docker-on-codeship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czeildi.github.io/2017/09/17/r-pkg-check-with-docker-on-codeship/</guid>
      <description>Motivation At Emarsys we have several internal private R packages which are essential to our day-to-day work. They are also under constant development. We want to work on these in a collaborative and safe way. Fast and trustworthy CI &amp;amp; CD are essential: they reduce the cost and risk of adding a small but useful feature to one of our packages.
Although in the R community Travis is the standard for CI, at Emarsys the whole company uses Codeship happily so we wanted to give it a go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R pkg development alongside packrat</title>
      <link>https://czeildi.github.io/2017/08/02/r-pkg-development-alongside-packrat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czeildi.github.io/2017/08/02/r-pkg-development-alongside-packrat/</guid>
      <description>I use packrat for all my projects at Emarsys so for our internal packages as well as it eases collaboration. During package development there are numerous packages which come handy during development but not needed for usage. These are usually listed under the Suggests or Enhances field in the DESCRIPTION file. But should these be tracked with packrat as well?
In my opinion, it depends. If it is testthat or roxygen2 probably everyone contributing to the package will use it so it makes sense to track with packrat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>