<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on experiments with R</title>
    <link>https://ildiczeller.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on experiments with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 15:32:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ildiczeller.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://ildiczeller.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 15:32:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ildiczeller.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description> My name is Ildi Czeller and I work as a Data Scientist at Emarsys in the Budapest office since I graduated as a mathematician from ELTE. Besides my work at Emarsys I am a mentor and organizer at Techcamp. I am also a proud alumna and supporter of The Joy of Thinking Foundation.
List of talks and publications Talks  useR! 2019 Toulouse 2019 July: ropsec: a package for easing operations security for the R user  slides on speakerdeck video  satRday Belgrade 2018 October: The essentials to work with object-oriented systems in R  slides on speakerdeck, slides on github  European R Users Meeting 2018 May: Clean R Code workshop held with Jenő Pál (@paljenczy)  materials  European R Users Meeting 2018 May: The essentials to work with object-oriented systems in R  slides on speakerdeck, slides on github video  Budapest BI Forum conference 2017 November: Message send time optimization  slides on speakerdeck, slides on github  BURN meetup 2017 October: custom ggplot2 theme  slides  RLadies meetup 2017 September: shiny introduction  materials  RLadies meetup 2017 June: shiny introduction  materials  Startup Safary Budapest 2017 April  slides  BURN meetup 2016 December: shiny modules  materials   Publications  From 0 to 5: our journey of building an R-package ecosystem Weekend bias in send time optimisation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ildiczeller.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ildiczeller.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me       code{white-space: pre;} pre:not([class]) { background-color: white; }  if (window.hljs) { hljs.configure({languages: []}); hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad(); if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) { window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0); } }  h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>